Guide to the St. Paul's United Methodist Church records, 1821-2009.
St. Paul's United Methodist Church records, 1821-2009.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
St. Paul's United Methodist Church records, 1821-2009.
St. Paul's United Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.)
17.7 cubic ft.
Institutional records, reports, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are membership and probation records, records of marriages and baptisms; minutes, treasurers' reports, and various business and legal papers of the Official Board; stewards' minutes and accounts and other financial records; trustees' minutes; correspondence, treasurer's reports, and memoranda; accounts of the Sabbath School Society and later Sunday School records; constitution of the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor and its membership records; minutes of the Ladies Social Union, the Ladies' and Pastor's Christian Union, and the Ladies Aid Society; record of the Woman's Home Missionary Society, the India Missionary Society, and the Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society, and minutes, a scrapbook, and miscellany of the Women's Society of Christian Service; and membership records of St. Paul Chapter No. 5 of the Methodist Brotherhood. Also included are many of the same type of records from the other Methodist Churches in Ithaca.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1879 the Seneca Street Methodist Church moved to State Street (Ithaca, New York) and was renamed the State Street Methodist Church. This congregation merged with the First Methodist (Episcopal) Church in 1961 and has since become St. Paul's United Methodist Church, which is located on the corner of Aurora and Court Streets, Ithaca.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are membership and probation records (1825-81), records of marriages (1821-81) and baptisms (1821-76); minutes, treasurers' reports, and various business and legal papers of the Official Board (1833-1952); stewards' minutes and accounts (1851-1918) and other financial records (1872-1940); trustees' minutes (1925-49); correspondence, treasurer's reports, and memoranda (1952-58) concerning the use of the building fund; accounts of the Sabbath School Society (1827-43) and later Sunday School records (1869-1961), including attendance books, secretary's minutes of the Loyal Daughters' Class (1916-56) and minutes of the Sunday School Board (1922-26) and the Commission on Education (1957-61); an undated constitution of the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor and its membership records (ca. 1873-94); minutes of the Ladies Social Union (1873-1902), the Ladies' and Pastor's Christian Union (1875-80), and the Ladies Aid Society (1916-40); minutes, treasurers' reports, attendance books, and accounts of the Woman's Home Missionary Society (1883-1940), the India Missionary Society (1896-1904), and the Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society (1911-20, 1932-36), and minutes, a scrapbook, and miscellany (1940-62) of the Women's Society of Christian Service, which was formed in 1940 by the merger of the earlier women's organizations; and membership records of St. Paul Chapter No. 5 of the Methodist Brotherhood (1905-12).
Also, copies of the monthly newspaper, THE CHURCH HELPER (1889-1937), weekly church calendars (1924-59, and the weekly newsletter, THE FIRST CHURCH HELPER (1943-57, 1959); minutes and accounts of the Quarterly Conference (1844-1915, 1939-50) and annual meetings (1950-56); and Central New York Conference minutes (1896-1953) and yearbooks (1954-63). Also included are many of the same type of records from the other Methodist Churches in Ithaca, including the Seneca Street Methodist Church (1851-79), the State Street Methodist Church (1879-1961), including an outline of the plan of merger with the First Methodist Church. Also, the centennial history of the First Methodist Church (1920) and other typescript and printed matter concerning Methodism in Ithaca; six architect's drawings (1944 and n.d.) for the Aurora Street church; and scattered issues of Protestant newspapers published in the Northeast. Also, pamphlets and reports for the First Methodist Church, 1907-1958, and annual reports, 1948-1993.
SUBJECTS
Names:
St. Paul's United Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.); First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Sabbath School Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Sunday School.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Loyal Daughters' Class.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Sunday School Board.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Commission on Education.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Ladies' Social Union.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Ladies Aid Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Woman's Missionary Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). India Missionary Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Woman's Home Missionary Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Women's Society of Christian Service.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society.; First Methodist Church (Ithaca, N.Y.). Ladies' and Pastor's Christian Union.; Methodist Brotherhood. St. Paul Chapter No. 5.; Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor (Ithaca, N.Y.).
Titles:
Church helper.; First church helper.
Subjects:
Methodism.; Methodists -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Missionaries.; Religious social work.; Sunday schools.; Women in church work.; Women in missionary work.; Methodist Women.; Church charities; Methodism; Methodist women; Methodists; Missionaries; Sunday schools; Women in church work; Women in missionary work
Places:
New York (State) -- Ithaca
Form and Genre Terms:
Accounts.; Architectural drawings.; Scrapbooks.; Vital statistics records.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Permission of the St. Paul's United Methodist Church office required by researchers not affiliated with the church.
CONTAINER LIST
- Ecclesiastical Register of the Methodist Episcopal Church in Ithaca - Records of Marriages and Baptisms, 1821-1845; Manuscript Volume (Box 1)
  Board Records
- Annual Record of Members of M. E. Church in the Ithaca Station, 1828-1841; Manuscript Volume (Box 1)
- Receiving Book (List of Members and Probationers) of the M. E. Church of Ithaca Station, 1828; Manuscript Volume (Box 1)
- A General Alphabetical Register of Members Belonging to the M. E. Church in Ithaca with Register of Baptisms and Marriages, 1842-1865; Manuscript Volume (Box 2)
- General record - Seneca St. M.. E. Church Record of baptisms and marriages, probationers, members (revised 1873), 1850-1865; Manuscript Volume (Box 2)
- Record of Aurora St. M. E. Church (members), 1864-1871; Manuscript Volume (Box 3)
- Historical record of M. E. Church, 1864-1876; Manuscript Volume (Box 3)
  9 departments - historical, probationers' class, alphabetical list of members, chronological list of members, pastoral and statistical, baptisms, marriages, appendix
- Comprehensive Church record of M. E. Church, 1875-1881; Manuscript Volume (Box 3)
- Record of State st. M. E. Church, 1881-1894; Manuscript Volume (Box 3)
- General Class Book, 1825-1827; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Minutes of the Official Board, 1833-10-21-1856-12-08; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Meetings and Accounts, 1835-1872; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Minutes of Leaders and Stewards, 1872-04-22-1880-04-05; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Recording Steward's Book - Seneca St. M. E. and State St. M. E., 1874-09-13-1912-09-17; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Minutes and Treasurer's reports, 1894-03-29-1902-12-01; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Board of Trustees of State St. M. E., 1893-1925; Manuscript Volume (Box 4)
- Official Board records, 1880-10-1902-09; Manuscript Volume (Box 5)
- Official Board records, 1902-1909; Manuscript Volume (Box 5)
- Official records, 1914-10-12-1925-12-25; Manuscript Volume (Box 5)
- Minutes of Official Board, 1910-1931; Manuscript Volume (Box 6)
- Board of Trustees Minutes, 1924-1945; Manuscript Volume (Box 6)
- Board of Trustees Minutes, 1926-1942; Manuscript Volume (Box 6)
- First Methodist Official Board, 1934-1939; Manuscript Volume (Box 6)
- Business Papers, 16 pcs., 1867-1908; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 14 pcs., 1915-1932; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 35 pcs., 1937-1945; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 43 pcs., 1946-1947; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 44 pcs., 1948-05-1949; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 44 pcs., 1949-06-1949-12; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Business Papers, 21 pea., 1950-1951; In Jute Folders (Box 7)
- Minutes of Official Board of First M. E., 1939-11-1943-07; Manuscript Volume (Box 7)
- 1939-11-1944-06 (Box 7)
- First M. E. Board of Trustees' Minutes, 1945-1949; Manuscript Volume (Box 7)
- Board Minutes, 1944-1947; Manuscript Volume (Box 7)
- Official Board Minutes, 1947-1948-06; Manuscript Volume (Box 7)
- Official Board Minutes, 1948-1949; Manuscript Volume (Box 7)
- Official Board Minutes, 1949-07-1952-03; Manuscript Volume (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - official board papers, 33 pcs., 1949-1950; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - official board papers, 37 pcs., 1951; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - off'icial board papers, 37 pcs., 1952; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - official board papers, 49 pcs., 1953; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - official board papers, 39 pcs., 1954; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- State St. M. E. - official board papers, 30 pcs., 1955-1961; In Jute Folders (Box 8)
- Black notebook - Finance, 1953-1958; Manuscript Volume (Box 8)
  Board Papers
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 38 pcs., 1952-01-1952-02; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 52 pcs., 1952-08-1952-10; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 58 pcs., 1952-11-1952-12; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 37 pcs., 1953-01-1953-07; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 16 pcs., 1953-08-1953-12; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 56 pcs., 1954-01-1954-06; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 42 pcs., 1954-07-1954-12; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 22 pcs., 1955-01-1955-06; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 24 pcs., 1955-07-1955-12; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 25 pcs., 1956-01-1956-03; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 34 pcs., 1956-03-1956-04; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 34 pcs., 1956-05-1956-08; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 27 pcs., 1956-09-1956-12; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Board of Trustees, building fund, etc. 42 pcs., 1957; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Budget. 33 pcs., 1957-1957; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Merger Plan, 23 pcs., 1961; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Business and Board Papers, 36 pcs., 1955; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
  State Street Methodist
- Business and Board Papers, 39 pcs., 1956; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Business and Board Papers, 32 pcs., 1957; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Business and Board Papers, 37 pcs., 1958; In Jute Folders (Box 9)
- Black Notebook, 1959-1964; Manuscript Volume (Box 9)
- Minutes of Board of Stewards, 1851-1865; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
  Accounts (1851-1915)
- Church Treasurer, 1872-1874; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- G. W. Frost's Account Book, 1874-1898; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Treasurer of Poor Fund, 1894-1918; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Ledger Accounts of Church Building Fund by George Frost, Undated; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Journal Accounts of George Frost, treas., 1898-1913; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Day Book (accounts), 1896-1924; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Church Treasurer, 1903-1915; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Sale of First M. E. Church Bonds, 1908-1909; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Stewards' minutes and accounts [transfered, 9/15/66, from Acc. # 2647], 1904-1908; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Steward's Accounts, 1908-1913; Manuscript Volume (Box 10)
- Account Book, 1913-1914; Manuscript Volume (Box 11)
  Accounts (1913-1940)
- Board of Stewards, 1913-1918; Manuscript Volume (Box 11)
- Minutes of Finance Committse, 1916-1917; Manuscript Volume (Box 11)
- Accounts, 1914-1922; Manuscript Volume (Box 11)
- Financial Secretary Record, 1930-1940; Manuscript Volume (Box 11)
- Secretary's Reports of Loyal Daughters, 1916-09-1925-06; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
  Loyal Daughter's Class, Sunday School
- Secretary's Reports of Loyal Daughters, 1934-09-1938-04; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Secretary's Reports of Loyal Daughters, 1938-1944; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Minutes of Loyal Daughters, 1944-1948; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Minutes of Loyal Daughters, 1949-1956; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Sabbath School Society Treasurer's Accounts, 1827-1943; In Jute Folders (Box 12)
- Aurora St. Sunday School, 1869-1875; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- "Rool Book", 1876-1881; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Members' List, 1890-1895; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Sunday School Library Fund Papers, 19 pcs., 1896-1897; In Jute Folders (Box 12)
- Attendance record of Sunday School, Class #6, 1900; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Record of Sunday School, 1907; Manuscript Volume (Box 12)
- Sunday School Records (Kindergarten, Primary, Intermediate, Senior, Transfers, Withdrawn), 1909-1913; Folders (Box 12)
- Sunday School Minutes (Board), 1922-1926; Notebooks (Box 12)
- Sunday School Minutes (Commission on Education), 1957-01-21-1961-01-09; Notebooks (Box 12)
- Constitution of the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, Undated; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
  C. E., Social Union, Ladies Aid
- Secretary's Book of the "Social Union", 1873-1885; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- Secretary's Book of the "Social Union", 1873-1894; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- Ladies' Social Union Minutes, 1881-1890; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- Secretary's Book, 1898-1902; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- Secretary's Book of Ladies' Aid of Seneca St. M. E. Church, 1865-1879; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
  Ladies' Aid, Misc. (1865-1912)
- Ladies's and Pastor's Christian Union Minutes (First M. E.), 1875-1880; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- 1893-1897 (Box 13)
- St. Paul Chapter No. 5 of the Methodist Brotherhood (First M. E.) Membership Roll and Personal Record of Members, 1906-1912; Manuscript Volume (Box 13)
- Ladie's Aid Minutes (First M. E.), 1916-1931; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
  Ladies' Aid (1916-1940)
- Ladies's Aid Society, 1931-1940; Notebook (Box 14)
- Constitution, duties, clippings, 1932-1940; Notebook (Box 14)
- Misc. papers, 14 pcs., 1921-1933; Folders (Box 14)
- Woman's Home Missionary Society minutes, 1883-1896; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
  Woman's Home Missionary Society
- Treasurer's Book of W. H. M. S., 1884-1893; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
- Attendance Book, 1896-1908; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
- Minutes, 1896-1903; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
- Secretary's Minutes, 1903-1915; Manuscript Volume (Box 14)
- Attendance Book, 1908-1919; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1940
- W. H. M. S., 1915-1923; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1941
- W. H. M. S. of StatA St. Church, 1917-1924; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1942
- W. H. M. S. of State St. Church, 1924-1936; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1943
- W. H. M S. (First M. E.) Minutes, 1932-1938; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1944
- Woman's Home Missionary Society Minutes (First M. E.), 1938-1940; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1945
- W. H. M. S. Accounts, Undated; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1946
- W. H. M. S. Misc. Financial paperst 31 pcs., 1935-1939; Folder (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1947
- Membership cards, cancelled checks, etc., 105 pcs., 1937-1940; Folder (Box 15)
  Missionary Societies, 1896-1948
- Minutes, 1896-1900; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
  India Missionary Society
- Minutes, 1901-1904; Manuscript Volume (Box 15)
- Woman's Foreign Missionary Society of the Seneca St. M. E., 1876; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
  W. F. M. S. (1876-1940)
- W. F. M. S. of Aurora St. Dues Book, 1877-1880; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. - Recording Secretary's Book, 1887-1895; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. - Recording Secretary's Book, 1895-1907; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. - Recording Secretary's Book, 1906-1911; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. - Record of Minutes, 1911-1921; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. - Record of Members, 1913-1918; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- 1907-1920 (Box 16)
- 1917-1931, Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. Minutes, 1921-1930; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. Accounts, 1930-1936; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- Young Woman's F. M. s. (State st.), 1927-1932; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- W. F. M. S. Minutes, 1930-1940; Manuscript Volume (Box 16)
- Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society, 1932-1936; Manuscript Volume (Box 17)
  Woman's Foreign Missionary Society (1911-1940)
- W. F. M. S. Accounts, 1935-1940; Manuscript Volume (Box 17)
- Evening Auxiliary W. F. M. S., 1937-1940; Manuscript Volume (Box 17)
- Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society Minutes, 34 pcs., 1911-1913; Folders (Box 17)
- Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society Minutes, 20 pcs., 1914-1915; Folders (Box 17)
- Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society Minutes, 30 pcs., 1916-1918; Folders (Box 17)
- Young Woman's Foreign Missionary Society Minutes, 24 pcs., 1919-1920; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 19 pcs., 1911-1919; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 22 pcs., 1920; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 29 pcs., 1921; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 29 pcs., 1922-1923; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 34 pcs., 1924-1926; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 22 pcs., 1927; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 21 pcs., 1927; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 27 pcs., 1929-1930; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 31 pcs., 1931-1935; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Misc. Papers, 27 pcs., Undated; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Programs, 60 pcs., Undated; Folders (Box 17)
- W. F. M. S. Certificates, 2 pcs., 1931; Cardboard Tube (Box 18)
- 1940-1942 (Box 18)
- Records of W. S. C. S., 1940-1943; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
  Woman's Society of Christian Service
- Minutes of Units III & IV of W. S. C. S., 1940-1948; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1942-1943; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1943-1943; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1945-1947; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- North Central Unit Record of Meetings, 1945-1955; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1947-1949; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1949-1954; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- W. S. C. S. Misc. papers, 10 pcs., 1947-1948; Folders (Box 18)
- W. S. C. S. Misc. papers, 49 pcs., 1951; Folders (Box 18)
- W. S. C. S. Misc. papers, 28 pcs., 1952; Folders (Box 18)
- W. S. C. S. Misc. papers, 34 pcs., 1953-1956; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 27 pcs., 1956-08-1956-12; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 26 pcs., 1957-01-1957-07; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 21 pcs., 1957-08-1957-12; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 28 pcs., 1958-01-1958-08; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 22 pcs., 1958-09-1958-12; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of Regular and Executive meetings of W. S. C. S., 25 pcs., 1959-01-1959-05; Folders (Box 18)
- Minutes of W. S. C. S., 1954-1956; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Minutes of Circle 5 of W. S. C. S., 1955-1962; Manuscript Notebook (Box 18)
- Church Helper, Vol. 1 & 2, 1889-1891; Bound Volume (Box 19)
  Monthly Periodicals (1889-1895)
- Church Helper, Vol. 1 & 2, 1889-1891; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 1 & 2, 1889-1891; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3 & 4, 1891-1893; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3 & 4, 1891-1893; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3, 4, & 5, 1891-1894; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3, 4, 5 & 6, 1891-1895; Bound Volume (Box 19)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3-10, 1891-1899; Bound Volume (Box 20)
- Church Helper, Vol. 3-12, 1891-1901; Bound Volume (Box 20)
- Church Helper, Vol. 5-8, 1893-1897; Bound Volume (Box 20)
- Church Helper, Vol. 6 & 7, 1894-1896; Bound Volume (Box 20)
- Church Helper, Vol. 9-12, 1897-1901; Bound Volume (Box 20)
- Church Helper, Vol. 13-15, 1901-1904; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 13-22, 1901-1911; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 16-19, 1904-1908; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 20-22, 1908-1911; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 23-27, 1911-1915; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 23-28, 1911-1915; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 28-32, 1916-1920; Bound Volume (Box 21)
- Church Helper, Vol. 29-40, 1917-1928; Bound Volume (Box 22)
- Church Helper, Index Vol. 1-35, 1889-1924; Bound Volume (Box 22)
- Church Helper, Vol. 33-38, 1921-1926; Bound Volume (Box 22)
- Church Helper, Vol. 39-42, 1927-1930; Bound Volume (Box 22)
- Church Helper (Monthly), 1903-1937; Loose Copies (Box 23)
- The Church Helper Misc. Issues, 1938-1945; Loose Copies (Box 24)
  Newsletters
- First Church Helper (Weekly), Complete, 1943-1948; Loose Copies (Box 24)
- First Church Helper (Lacking 1958), 1949-1959; Loose Copies (Box 25)
- Church Calendar of Worship (Unbound), 1924-06-08-1926; Loose Copies (Box 25)
- Church Calendar of Worship (Unbound), 1927-1945; Loose Copies (Box 26)
- Church Calendar of Worship (Unbound), 1946-1955; Loose Copies (Box 27)
- Church Calendar of Worship (Unbound), 1956-1959; Loose Copies (Box 28)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 1-7, 1869-1874; Bound Volume (Box 28)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 8-15, 1875-1882; Bound Volume (Box 28)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 16-20, 1883-1887; Bound Volume (Box 28)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 21-24, 1888-1897; Bound Volume (Box 29)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 25-28, 1892-1895; Bound Volume (Box 29)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 29-33, 1896-1900; Bound Volume (Box 29)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 34-38, 1901-1905; Bound Volume (Box 29)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 39-43, 1906-1910; Bound Volume (Box 30)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 44-48, 1911-1915; Bound Volume (Box 30)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 49-53, 1916-1920; Bound Volume (Box 30)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 54-58, 1921-1925; Bound Volume (Box 30)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, Vol. 59-63, 1926-1930; Bound Volume (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference, 1881; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference, 1882; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference, 1883; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference, 1884; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference, 1885; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, 1886; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, 1887; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, 1888; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)
- Central N. Y. Annual Conference Minutes, 1890; Pamphlets (Unbound) (Box 31)